{
    "trivia": {
        "0": {
            "question": "Which of these movies is NOT based on a board game?",
            "choices": ["Ouija",
                "Jumanji",
                "Battleship",
                "Clue"
            ],
            "answer": 1,
            "fact": "Jumanju the movie is about a boardgame, and there was a Jumanji game released in 1995 around the same time as the movie, but it the movie itself was actually based on the 1981 novel of the same name by Chris Van Allsburg."
        },
        "1": {
            "question": "Which of these is the cheapest group of properties in Monopoly?",
            "choices": ["Dark Purple", "Light Purple", "Red", "Light Blue", "Dark Blue"],
            "answer": 0,
            "fact": "The Dark Purple properties - Mediterranean and Baltic Ave. - are the cheapest properties in Monopoly; they only cost $120 to buy.  The other colors, in order, are:  Light Blue - $320; Light Purple (Maroon/Pink) - $440; Orange - $560; Red - $700; Dark Blue - $750; Yellow - $800; Green- $920."
        },
        "2": {
            "question": "Three of the following are different names for the same game:  Which one is a different game?",
            "choices": ["Shogun", "Samurai Swords", "Ikusa", "James Clavell's Shogun"],
            "answer": 3,
            "fact": "Although there is a boardgame called James 'Clavell's Shogun', it is a different game.   The original name for Ikusa was 'Shogun', but it was later changed to Samurai Swords due to copyright issues with James Clavell's novel of the same name, then later changed to it's current name of Ikusa. "
        },
        "3": {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a common characteristic of 'Euro' style board games?",
            "choices": ["Tile Placement", "Set Collection", "Player Elimination", "Area Control", "Worker Placement"],
            "answer": 2,
            "fact": "A Eurogame, also called a German-style or Euro-style board game, generally have indirect player interaction and abstract physical components. Euro-style games emphasize strategy while downplaying luck and conflict. They tend to have economic themes rather than military and usually keep all the players in the game until it ends."
        },
        "4": {
            "question": "Which of these games features dice drafting as a game mechanic?",
            "choices": ["Seasons", "7 Wonders", "Dominion", "Button Men"],
            "answer": 0,
            "fact": "In Seasons, the first player rolls a number of dice.  Each player in turn then selects one of the rolled values, and passes the rest of the dice along to the next player.  This is known as dice drafting."
        },
        "5": {
            "question": "How many color groups are there in monopoly?",
            "choices": ["6", "8", "10", "12"],
            "answer": 1,
            "fact": "The property colors are Dark Purple, Light Blue, Orange, Red, Yellow, Green, Dark Blue, and the last group... this group originally Maroon when the game was created, then changed to Light Purple, and most recently to Pink."
        },
        "6": {
            "question": "How many points is an X worth in scrabble?",
            "choices": ["4", "6", "8", "10"],
            "answer": 2,
            "fact": "J and X are both worth 8 points in Scrabble.  Only Q and Z are worth 10."
        },
        "7": {
            "question": "What is the British name for the game Chutes and Ladders?",
            "choices": ["Chutes and Stairs", "Slides and Ladders", "Chutes and Baskets", "Snakes & Ladders"],
            "answer": 3,
            "fact": "Nothing here."
        },
        "8": {
            "question": "What is Parcheesi's nation of origin?",
            "choices": ["Iran", "Turkey", "India", "Greece"],
            "answer": 2,
            "fact": "The original game, Pachisi, is a cross and circle board game that originated in medieval India, which has been described as the 'national game of India'."
        },
        "9": {
            "question": "What is the maximum number of players in Chinese Checkers?",
            "choices": ["6", "2", "8", "5"],
            "answer": 0,
            "fact": "Nothing here."
        },
        "10": {
            "question": "Which kind of game makes my wife want to run away?",
            "choices": ["Really long ones", "Really thinky ones", "Really futzy ones", "All of the above"],
            "answer": 3,
            "fact": "She really does enjoy boardgames.  She's not just humoring me."
        },
        "11": {
            "question": "Which of these is not a 19th Century boardgame?",
            "choices": ["Science in Sport or the Pleasures of Astronomy,<br>A New Instructive Pastime", "Tzolk'in, The Mayan Calendar", "The Crystal Palace Game, A Voyage Round the<br> World, An entertaining excursion in search of<br> knowledge, whereby Geography is Made Easy", "The Wonders of the World", "The New Game of the Elephant and Castle,<br>or Travelling in Asia"],
            "answer": 1,
            "fact": "'Tzolk'in, The Mayan Calendar' was published in 2012."
        }
    }
}